Nitin Lakra

PERSONAL DATA

DATE OF BIRTH: 24 May 1999
PHONE: +91 9078373252

EMAIL: nitinlakra123@gmail.com WEB: darc-coder.github.io

ABOUT ME

Software Development Engineer with 2 years of experience in the industry. Enthusiastic team player, a fast learner with creative problem-solving skills, and good coding skills. Aspiring to achieve organizational goals and reach the peak of success.

EDUCATION

JUNE 2020 B.Tech in COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING,

National Institute Of Technology, Rourkela

CGPA: 6.51/10

MARCH 2016 Intermediate in SCIENCE,

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Jharsuguda

PERCENTAGE: 78.00

MARCH 2014 Matriculation,

Jawahar Navodaya Vidyalaya, Jharsuguda

PERCENTAGE: 87.4

PROJECTS

FORGERY IMAGE DETECTION | APRIL 2019 - MAY 2020

Nowadays, image technology is rapidly growing. Many software are convenient for editing or tampering images. Using Forgery Image Detection we can detect

the forged images and we can prevent false news spreading.

BINGO GAME | AUGUST 2021 - OCTOBER 2021

Bingo (or Housie) Game is an online multiplayer game, The Game was created

so Friends and colleagues can play Bingo remotely.

PILLS BY NITZ | AUGUST 2022 - SEPTEMBER 2022

Pills is a Web based Music App developed to listen to songs and music from your favourite artists The app was created using React and PWA technologies allowing

it to be installed on your device like a regular application.

CRUD Browser October 2022 - February 2023

CRUD browser is an internal Angular App, the App is created using modern

angular* features such as Reactive programming & lazy loaded Modules to en-

hance App Load time and performance.

NAKAD APP | APRIL 2023 - PRESENT

Nakad App is an Enterprise web application for supply chain financing. The platform automates AR and AP reconciliation, providing a one-stop dashboard for balance confirmation, ledger procurement, reconciling the ledgers and dispute

resolutions.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MAY - JULY 2019 | CENTRAL DATA PROCESSING INTERN, DRDO CHANDIPUR

My Project was Real time Image Encryption using Cellular Automata at CDP, DRDO

Chandipur.

OCTOBER 2020 - APRIL 2023 | JUNIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER, NETCRACKER TECHNOLOGY

Worked on PL/SQL procedures to implement business logic. Worked on Delphi to create application UI. Developed features using Delphi & Oracle technologies to enhance our core product (Rating and Billing Manager) and performed unit testing for the imple-

mented features. Worked using Angular to develop CRUD Browser.

APRIL 2023 - PRESENT | SOFTWARE DEVELOPEMENT ENGINEER, NAKAD

Working at FrontEnd with React to develop application to build a digital Supply Chain

Finance Platform.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

General Programming: | Python, CSS, Javascript, TypeScript, React - Advanced

C++, Java, Node JS, Angular, PLSQL - Intermediate React Native , UNIX, Delphi, Flutter - Beginner

Databases: Oracle, My SQL

Other Software: | Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro, MS Office, Latex

SOFT SKILLS

LANGUAGES English - Fluent

Hindi - Mother Tongue Odia - Basic Fluency

SOFT SKILLS Problem Solving

Analytical Thinking

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

SCOUT AND GUIDE

Captain, 2015

The Scouts and Guides is a voluntary, non-political, educational movement for young people, open to all without distinction of origin of origin, race or creed. I was captain of our School Scout And Guide Troop.

SCHOLARSHIPS AND CERTIFICATES

JANUARY 2021 You Have Made the Difference FEBRUARY 2018 Coordinator in NITRUTSAV

Before 2016 Won Various School Level Essay Writing Competition.

INTERESTS AND ACTIVITIES

Interests: Internet Surfing, Photography

Activities: Singing, Playing Games

Hobbies: Football, Swimming, Watching and Learning Tech